

A.K.M. Shahab Uddin

shahab.ibaju@gmail.com 🔀

+8801710394178

20/1 Kawlar West, (Flat no-6A), Khilkhet, Dakshin Khan, Dhaka-1229.

www.linkedin.com/in/sajidshahab in

KPI oriented marketing & sales professional with blending of Telco and FMCG industry & having more than 8 years' experience in sales & marketing arena. Strategic minded individual with a keen sense of competitive intelligence and market analysis. Highly active ability to communicate sales tactics and strategies to other professionals through strong analysis & presentation skills. Driving business having growth in mindset, deliver KPIs, build up proper team, Having expertise on MS Office & G-Suite to analyze business data.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jita Social Business Bangladesh Ltd. (January 2020 – Continue)

Manager, Operations

- Assist OPS team to improve Operation revenue in current scope & Develop OPS related process and roll out as per plan.
- Develop team monitoring and reporting plan & process and Assist in field based audit/investigation.
- Qualitative & quantitative analysis of sales channels to measure performance of sales team and create the visibility to senior management team
- To prepare a periodic progress and monitoring report as per requirement.
- Regular correspondence with regional and HQ management and other stakeholders.
- Initiate and Implement programs/projects to make growth in business.

Achievement

- Best Employee Award-2021
- Successfully converted sales process into automation system.
- Transform all sort of database & reporting into G-suite to work with real-time data.

Marico Bangladesh Ltd. (January 2019 – December 2019)

Territory Manager

- Distribution Management, Warehouse management & ensure Distributor ROI.
- Taking strategy to achieve month and block wise secondary & primary target (Volume & BPM).
- Increase and manage Amar Dokan, Milonmela & Execute NPLP and category availability.
- FF recruitment and Development & strong monitoring on sales automation to track everyday activity.
- Ensure trade marketing activities on various channel.
- To execute PSR, Stockiest to cover untapped market & remote areas.

○ Robi Axiata Ltd.(2015-2019)

Sales Manager (August 2017 – January 2019) Trade Marketing Manager (RTM) (Acting) - (2017) Territory Manager (2016-2017)

Territory Executive (2015-2016)

- Attain Area Sales Target by ensuring proper distribution of products and services and implementation of retail &other channel activities.
- Develop and manage the operation of third party distribution channels as per the guidelines.
- Acute implementation of SFA (Sales Force Automation) tools.
- Working on merger companies by maintaining proper distribution of both channel.
- Establishment of Biometric operation through retail engagement
- Arrange & Execute Trade marketing activities & ensure trade offer to key channel & end channel.
- Work closely with 3p about merchandising materials, planning & designs.
- Preparing and submitting accurate and complete sales forecasts and pipeline reports
- Work as a team leader & accelerating whole team in a plan basis.

Achievement

- Best Performer award in Q2 2017, Q4 2017 and Q2 2018 in Nationally
- Selected as R-venturist in R-venture program by Robi Axiata Ltd for innovative idea.
- Achieving Mission Possible award -Best Sm in year 2017.
- Achieving national champion award in 2018.
- Star Performer Award in Q1 2017 and Q4 2017.
- Achieving Various KPI wise award in North Eastern Cluster.









EDUCATION

OMaster of Business Administration (MBA)

2018

IBA (Institute of Business Administration), Jahangirnagar University. Major in Marketing, Minor in Supply Chain, **CGPA** – **3.12**

OBachelor of Business Administration (BBA)

2014

Dhaka City College, Major in Marketing, CGPA - 3.46

O Higher Secondary Certificate (H.S.C.)

2009

Dhaka City College, Dhaka, Group Business Studies, GPA - 4.80

Secondary School Certificate (S.S.C.)

2007

Silonia High School, Group: Business Studies, G.P.A. – 5.00

Training & Professional Workshop

- Did 90 Days lean startup workshop including 4 days long incubation session by Robi & Malaysian Code Ar.my.
- Having 3 months Internship experience from Brand department of Akij Food & Beverage Ltd.
- Taking 4 days Training about Territory management.
- Taking 3 Days Training of Sales Strategy & Planning
- Having 2 Days TDOM workshop experience about business development.
- Actively engaged as a trainee in workshop of B-Green project.

Achievement & Involvement

- Achieving various National Award during employment time of ROBI for outstanding works & outcomes.
- Shortlisted on R-venture program on Robi Axiata Ltd for innovative idea.
- Champion in IBP Business Plan competition
- Involve with E-commerce & F-commerce community
- Involve as a volunteer & learner in various program of Google Business Group
- Achieving 2nd position on lean startup contest is conducted by Malaysian Code ar.my.

Computer Competency

- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Power BI Access, Outlook,).
- G-Suit (Expert on G-Sheet)
- Data Analysis & Graphical Representation with Microsoft Excel & PowerPoint

Personal Details

1. Father's Name : A.K.M. Jashim Uddin

Mother's Name: Shahida Akhter
Date of Birth: 1st January, 1992

4. Religion : Islam

5. Nationality: Bangladeshi

6. Marital Status : Single

7. Permanent Address: Village: Dharmapur (Bhuiyan Bari), P.O. Silonia Bazar

Upazila: Dhagonbhuyian, District: Feni.

Reference

Dr. Md. Baktiar Rana

Professor, Institute of Business Administration, Jahangirnagar University E-mail- baktiar@juniv.edu Phone - 01726427768 Kazi Favzur Rahman

Regional sales manager, Coats Group Plc.

Email- fayzur.rahman@coats.com

Phone- 01817548529